MOINAK DAS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



34 44 77ST - New York, NY 11372





CAREER PROFILE

Software developer with 3 years of experience in website management and software development for non-profit origanizations. Capable instructor for programming, math, and science. Proficient in HTML, CSS, javascript, python, php, java, and C#. Have experience with Android Studio, Unity Game Engine, and Wordpress.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - MAY. 2019 - PRESENT

GREATER ASTORIA HISTORICAL SOCIETY - Long Island City, NY

Developed wordpress plugins to streamline website submission processes | Designed new origanization website: astorialic.org, tripling user traffic | Created software to automate day-to-day tasks and complete them in a fraction of their original time | Involved in the development and design of PC and mobile applications | Used Android Studio and Unity to develop prototypes for these applications | Effectively communicate ideas through powerpoints and documents

WEB DEVELOPER - SEP. 2020 - PRESENT

MARNI HALASA'S CITY COUNCIL CAMPAIGN - Manhattan, NY

Designed a Wordpress website to promote the campaign | Worked with the campaign team to effectively represent Ms. Halasa online

INSTRUCTOR - SEP. 2020 - PRESENT

STUYVESANT STUDY SOCIETY - Manhattan, NY

One on one tutoring with a fourth grade student | Created engaging lesson plans and online demonstrations

INSTRUCTOR - JUN. 2020 - SEPT. 2020

NEW YORK YOUTH TECHNOLOGY TEAM - Queens, NY

Taught children aged 11 - 14 how to code in python | Graded homework and classwork | Created lessons based on problem-solving and technique, cultivating a broader understanding of programming languages.

IT MEMBER - JAN. 2019 - JUN. 2020

STUYVESANT STUDENT UNION - Manhattan, NY

Managed IT help desk for the Student Union website | Managed website: Stuyacivities.org

INSTRUCTOR - JUN. 2019 - SEP. 2019

SCIENCE ADVENTURE KIDS – Manhattan, NY

Managed social media platforms | Responsible for animal care, cleanings, and feedings | Taught children aged 5-10 various topics in science | Helped children with disabilities keep up with instruction | Communicated effectively with both children and coworkers

CONTENT MANAGER - JAN. 2019 - JUN. 2020

STUYVESANT SPECTATOR WEB DEPARTMENT - Manhattan, NY

Responsible for the submissions of articles to the School newspaper website

EDUCATION

STUYVESANT HIGH SCHOOL (2018-2021) - Manhattan, NY

Relevant Coursework: IntroCS, AP Computer Science A

GPA: 4.0

BROOKLYN TECHNICAL HIGH SCHOOL (2017-2018) - Brooklyn, NY

Relevant Coursework: Designing and Drafting for Production

GPA: 4.0

SKILLS

Able to speak in Spanish and Bengali | Autodesk Certified Professional 2017-2021 | Experienced with Autodesk Inventor Professional, Fusion 360, and Blender | Great with kids, able to play the guitar, piano, drums, ukulele, and clarinet